<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Flatiron School Blog</title><link>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Flatiron School Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 15:35:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Importing Excel File with Pictures to React</title><link>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/importing-excel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 15:35:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/importing-excel/</guid><description>As my final capstone project for the Flatiron School boot camp I am working on building a testing app for an Aunt of mine who runs a small computer training school in Kolkata, India.
Part of the functionality of the website is for her to be able to upload prewritten test files in excel, containing image columns, to create the tests. After doing some google searching and research I found the ExcelJS package, which makes the process quite simple.</description></item><item><title>Three.js From A Beginner</title><link>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/three-js-beginning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 17:57:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/three-js-beginning/</guid><description>I did not expect to spend my day today the way that I did.
It started this morning when I began to think about what I want my portfolio web page to look like. I googled something along the lines of “software developer portfolio sites” and a few links came up with titles like “Best 20 Software Portfolio Examples”. I clicked on one and started scrolling, saw a site that looked cool, so I followed the link.</description></item><item><title>Javascript array.reduce() Method</title><link>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/array-method-reduce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 16:30:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/array-method-reduce/</guid><description>The past few weeks I have been consistantly forgetting the syntax for the array reduce method in Javascript. After googling it a number of times, I thought it might be helpful to write out a method for it here.
Why is the reduce() method used? It is used to interate over an array and return one value from a calculation done on each value.
For example, given the array of:</description></item><item><title>How I Got to a Software Engineering Bootcamp</title><link>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:31:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.katherineroll.com/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hello, welcome to my blog! My name is Katherine Roll and I am currently a student in a software engineering boot camp at the Flatiron school. It is a 15-week course that teaches the skills required to become a full stack engineer. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a crazy story, how I ended up here, writing code for hours every day.
To start, I graduated with a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in mathematics from the University of Massachusetts in 2019.</description></item></channel></rss>